Everything is covered in invisible ecosystems
كل شيء مغطى بنظام البيئي غير مرئي
made of tiny lifeforms: bacteria, viruses and fungi.
مكون من أشياء طبيعية: باكتيريا، فايروسات و الفطريات.
Our desks, our computers, our pencils, our buildings
مكاتبنا و كمبيوتراتنا، و أقلامنا، و مبانينا
all harbor resident microbial landscapes.
كلها ملاجئ للمايكروبات الطبيعية
As we design these things, we could be thinking
كما نقوم بتصميم هذه الأشياء،نستطيع ان نفكر
about designing these invisible worlds,
حول تصميم عوالم غير مرئية،
and also thinking about how they interact
و نفكر كيف تتفاعل مع بعضها البعض
with our personal ecosystems.
مع نظامنا البيئي الخاص.
Our bodies are home to trillions of microbes,
أجسامنا هي منزل لبلايّن من المايكروبات،
and these creatures define who we are.
و هذه الكائنات تحدد من نكون.
The microbes in your gut can influence your weight and your moods.
المايكروبات التي في امعائنا تحدد وزننا و مزاجنا.
The microbes on your skin can help boost your immune system.
المايكروبات التي في الجلد تحسن نظام المناعة الذي لديكم.
The microbes in your mouth can freshen your breath,
المايكروبات التي في فمك تنعش رائحة فمك
or not,
أو لا،
and the key thing is that our personal ecosystems
و الشيء المهم هو نظامنا البيئي الخاص
interact with ecosystems on everything we touch.
يتفاعل مع الأنظمة البيئية الأخرى كلما لمسناها.
So, for example, when you touch a pencil,
مثلا،عندما تلمس قلم رصاص،
microbial exchange happens.
التبادل المايكروبي يحدث.
If we can design the invisible ecosystems in our surroundings,
إذا كان بأمكاننا ان نصمم النظام البيئي الغير مرئي من حولنا،
this opens a path to influencing
هذا يفتح لنا طريق إلى التأثير
our health in unprecedented ways.
على صحتنا في طرق لا مثيل لها.
I get asked all of the time from people,
الناس دائماً يسألوني،
"Is it possible to really design microbial ecosystems?"
"هل هو ممكن ان نصمم النظام البيئي المايكروبي؟"
And I believe the answer is yes.
و انا اؤمن أن الجواب هو نعم.
I think we're doing it right now,
أعتقد أننا نفعلها الآن،
but we're doing it unconsciously.
لكننا نفعلها من غير قصد.
I'm going to share data with you
سأقوم بمشاركة بيانات معكم
from one aspect of my research focused on architecture
من إحدى جوانب بحثي التي تركز على الهندسة المعمارية
that demonstrates how, through both conscious
و التي توضح كيف، من خلال شيء مدرك
and unconscious design,
و الشيء الغير مدرك،
we're impacting these invisible worlds.
نحن نأثر على العالمم الغير مرئي.
This is the Lillis Business Complex at the University of Oregon,
هذا هو "ليليز بسنس كومبلكس" في جامعة أوريقون،
and I worked with a team of architects and biologists
و انا اعمل مع فريق مكون من مهندسين معمارين و علماء أحياء
to sample over 300 rooms in this building.
لنفترض ان هناك أكثر من ٣٠٠ غرفه في هذا المبنى.
We wanted to get something like a fossil record of the building,
كنا سنريد ان نأخذ شيء مثل سجل أحفوري لهذا المبنى،
and to do this, we sampled dust.
و لنفعل ذلك،نأخذ عينه من الغبار.
From the dust, we pulled out bacterial cells,
من الغبار، نسحب الخلايا البكتيرية،
broke them open, and compared their gene sequences.
فتحنا الخلايا، و قارناها بتسلسلها الجيني.
This means that people in my group
و هذا يعني آن الناس الذين في مجموعتي
were doing a lot of vacuuming during this project.
كانوا يكنسوا كثيرا طوال هذه الفترة.
This is a picture of Tim, who,
هذه صورة لتيم، و هو،
right when I snapped this picture, reminded me,
عندما صورت هذه الصورة، تذكرت،
he said, "Jessica, the last lab group I worked in
قال،"جيسيكا، آخر معمل كيميائي عملت فيه
I was doing fieldwork in the Costa Rican rainforest,
ذهبت لأعمل عمل ميداني في غابة 'كوستا ريكان'،
and things have changed dramatically for me."
و الأشياء تغيرت بشكل كبير بالنسبة لي."
So I'm going to show you now first what we found in the offices,
اولا سأريكم ماذا وجدنا في المكاتب،
and we're going to look at the data through a visualization tool
و سننظر للبيانات من خلال أداة التخيل
that I've been working on in partnership with Autodesk.
التي كنت اعمل عليها في شراكة مع الاوتودسك.
The way that you look at this data is,
الناحية التي انتم تنظرون إلى هذه البيانات،
first, look around the outside of the circle.
أولا، انظروا إلى الدائرة من الخارج.
You'll see broad bacterial groups,
سترون مجموعات باكتيريا عديدة،
and if you look at the shape of this pink lobe,
و اذا نظرتهم إلى شكل هذا الفص الوردي،
it tells you something about the relative abundance of each group.
هذا يخبرنا عن غزارة نسبية في كل مجموعة.
So at 12 o'clock, you'll see that offices have a lot of
لذلك في تمام الساعة ١٢،سترون انه يوجد العديد من
alphaproteobacteria, and at one o'clock
متقلبات ألفا في المكاتب، و في الساعة ١
you'll see that bacilli are relatively rare.
سترون ان العصيات نادرة جداً.
Let's take a look at what's going on in different space types in this building.
دعونا نأخذ نظرة إلى ماذا يحدث في أماكن مختلفة في هذا المبنى.
If you look inside the restrooms,
اذا نظرتهم الى دورة المياه من الداخل،
they all have really similar ecosystems,
جميعها لديها نظام بيئي متشابه،
and if you were to look inside the classrooms,
و اذا نظرتهم الى الفصول الدراسية من الداخل،،
those also have similar ecosystems.
هؤلاء أيضاً لديهم نظام بيئي متشابه.
But if you look across these space types,
لكن اذا نظرتهم الى أنواع الفراغات،
you can see that they're fundamentally different
ستلاحظون أنهم في الواقع مختلفين
from one another.
من بعض.
I like to think of bathrooms like a tropical rainforest.
افضل ان أعتقد ان دورات المياه هي مثل الغاباة الاستوائية.
I told Tim, "If you could just see the microbes,
أخبرت تيم،"اذا كان بأستطاعه ان يرى المايكروبات،
it's kind of like being in Costa Rica. Kind of."
أنها مثل كوننا في كوستا ريكا،نوع ما."
And I also like to think of offices as being a temperate grassland.
و أيضاً اعتقد ان المكاتب قد تكون مثل الأراضي العشبية المعتدلة.
This perspective is a really powerful one for designers,
وجهة النظر هذه جبارة لدى المصممين،
because you can bring on principles of ecology,
لأنك تستطيع جلب مبادئ لعلم البيئة،
and a really important principle of ecology is dispersal,
و مبادئ مهمة جداً لعلم البيئة تكون مشتتة،
the way organisms move around.
الطريقة التي تتحرك بها الكأنات
We know that microbes are dispersed around by people
نعلم ان المايكروبات متناثرة حول الناس
and by air.
و حول الجو.
So the very first thing we wanted to do in this building
لذلك اول شئ اردنا عمله في هذا المبنى
was look at the air system.
هو ان ننظر الى نظام الهواء.
Mechanical engineers design air handling units
المهندسين الميكانيكيين يصممون وحدات تدبيرالهواء
to make sure that people are comfortable,
لأتأكد ان الناس مرتاحون،
that the air flow and temperature is just right.
و ان الهواء يتدفق و ان درجة الحرارة مناسبة.
They do this using principles of physics and chemistry,
يفعلون ذلك بأستعمال مبادئ الفيزياء و كيمياء،
but they could also be using biology.
لكنهم يستطيعون استعمال الأحياء أيضاً.
If you look at the microbes
اذا نظرت الى المايكروبات
in one of the air handling units in this building,
التي في وحدة تدبير الهواء في هذا المبنى،
you'll see that they're all very similar to one another.
سترى أن جميعهم يتشابهون.
And if you compare this to the microbes
و اذا قارناها بالميكروبات
in a different air handling unit,
في وحدة تدبير هواء أخرى،
you'll see that they're fundamentally different.
سترى أنهم أساس مختلفين.
The rooms in this building are like islands in an archipelago,
الغرف في هذا المبنى مثل الجزر التي في أرخبيل
and what that means is that mechanical engineers
و هذا يعني ان المهندسين الميكانيكيين
are like eco-engineers, and they have the ability
هم مثل البيئة، و لديهم إلامكانية
to structure biomes in this building the way that they want to.
لهيكلة الكتلة الحيوية في هذا المبنى بالطريقة التي يريدونها.
Another facet of how microbes get around is by people,
وجيه أخرى لكيفية المايكروبات تتحرك حول الناس،
and designers often cluster rooms together
و المصممين غالبا يضعون كتل من الغرفة مع بعض
to facilitate interactions among people,
لتسهيل التفاعلات بين الناس،
or the sharing of ideas, like in labs and in offices.
أو تبادل الأفكار،مثل في مختبرات أو مكاتب.
Given that microbes travel around with people,
نظرا الى آن المايكروبات تتنقل حول الناس،
you might expect to see rooms that are close together
قد تتوقع ان ترى غرفا قريبة من بعض
have really similar biomes.
و لديها كتلة حيوية متشابه.
And that is exactly what we found.
و هذا بالضبط ما وجدناه.
If you look at classrooms right adjacent to one another,
اذا نظرت الى الفصول الدراسية المجاورة،
they have very similar ecosystems,
لديها نظام بيئي شبيه جداً،
but if you go to an office
لكن اذا ذهبت الى مكتب
that is a farther walking distance away,
والذي هو في أبعد مسافة مشي،
the ecosystem is fundamentally different.
النظام البيئي في الواقع مختلف.
And when I see the power that dispersal has
و عندما أرى قوة للتشتيت
on these biogeographic patterns,
على نمط الجغرافيا الحيوية،
it makes me think that it's possible
هذا يجعلني أعتقد أن أنه من الممكن
to tackle really challenging problems,
أن نتحدى مشاكل صعبة جداً في الحياة،
like hospital-acquired infections.
مثل المكتسبات التي تأتي من المستشفيات.
I believe this has got to be, in part,
أؤمن ان هذا يجب أن يكون،جزء من
a building ecology problem.
مشكلة بناء البيئية.
All right, I'm going to tell you one more story about this building.
حسنا سأخبرهم قصة أخرى عن هذا المبنى.
I am collaborating with Charlie Brown.
انا أتعاون مع 'شارلي براون'.
He's an architect,
هو مهندس معماري،
and Charlie is deeply concerned about global climate change.
و 'شارلي' مهتم جداً عن التغيرات التي تحدث بسبب الاكتباس الحراري.
He's dedicated his life to sustainable design.
لقد كرس حياته الى التصميم المحتمل.
When he met me and realized that it was possible for him
عندما التقى بي اكتشف ان بأمكانه ان
to study in a quantitative way
يدرس بطريقك كمية
how his design choices impacted
كيف كان اختياره للتصاميم هذه
the ecology and biology of this building,
البيئة و الأحياء لهذا البنى،
he got really excited, because it added a new dimension to what he did.
تحمس جداً،لان أضافت له بعد جديد للذي فعله.
He went from thinking just about energy
ذهب من التفكير عن الطاقة
to also starting to think about human health.
الى التفكير عن صحة الإنسان أيضاً.
He helped design some of the air handling systems
ساعد قليلاً بتصميم وحدة تدبير الهواء
in this building and the way it was ventilated.
في هذا المبنى و الطريقة التي كانت في التهوية
So what I'm first going to show you is
لذلك أول شيء سأريكم إياه هو
air that we sampled outside of the building.
عينات للهواء من خارج المبنى.
What you're looking at is a signature of bacterial communities
هذا الذي تنظرون إليه هو علامة لوجود مجتمعات للبكتيريا
in the outdoor air, and how they vary over time.
في الهواء الخارجي،و كيف يتفاوت مع الزمن.
Next I'm going to show you what happened
التالي سأريكم ماذا حدث
when we experimentally manipulated classrooms.
عندما نختبر الفصول الدراسية بصيغة تجريبية.
We blocked them off at night
نغلقها في الليل
so that they got no ventilation.
لذلك لا يدخل أي هواء
A lot of buildings are operated this way,
أغلب المباني تعمل بهذا الشكل
probably where you work,
أحتمال المكان الذي تعمل فيه،
and companies do this to save money on their energy bill.
و الشركات تعمل هذا للحفاظ على نقودهم و لا ترفع سعر فاتورة الكهرباء.
What we found is that these rooms remained relatively stagnant
الشيء الذي نجده هو ان الغرف تبقى راكدة نسبيا
until Saturday, when we opened the vents up again.
حتى يون السبت، عندما فتحنا التهوية مرة أخرى.
When you walked into those rooms,
عندما تدخل الى تلك الغرف،
they smelled really bad,
فتكون رائحتها سيئة،
and our data suggests that it had something to do with
و بياناتنا تقترح ان أسبب هو
leaving behind the airborne bacterial soup
أننا ندع باكتيريا الصابون
from people the day before.
من الناس الذين كانوا هنا اليوم الذي قبله.
Contrast this to rooms
اكتشف ان الغرف
that were designed using a sustainable passive design strategy
كانت مصممة بأستعمال طريقة تصميم متحملة
where air came in from the outside through louvers.
الهواء أتى من الخارج من خلال
In these rooms, the air tracked the outdoor air relatively well,
في هذه الغرف ،الهواء يعقبه من الخارج جيدا،
and when Charlie saw this, he got really excited.
و عندما رأه 'شارلي' ، تحمس جداً.
He felt like he had made a good choice
أحس و كأنه اتخذ اختيار جيد جداً
with the design process
مع عملية التصميم
because it was both energy efficient
لان كان كلا كفائه الطاقة
and it washed away the building's resident microbial landscape.
و قد اختفى المقيم المايكروبي الطبيعي لهذا المبنى.
The examples that I just gave you are about architecture,
الأمثلة التي أعطيتكم إياها كلها عن الهندسة المعمارية،
but they're relevant to the design of anything.
لكن أنها نسبية لتصميم أي شيء.
Imagine designing with the kinds of microbes that we want
تخيل باستطاعنا ان نصمم المايكروبات التي نريدها
in a plane
في مكان
or on a phone.
أو في هاتف نقال.
There's a new microbe, I just discovered it.
هنالك مايكروب جديد، و انا اكتشفته.
It's called BLIS, and it's been shown
اسمه 'بي ال أي اس'، و هو
to both ward off pathogens
من مسببات الأمراض
and give you good breath.
و يعطيك رائحة فم جيدة
Wouldn't it be awesome if we all had BLIS on our phones?
أليس سيكون رائع اذا كان لدينا 'بي ال اي اس' في هواتفها النقالة؟
A conscious approach to design,
تصميم منهجي واع،
I'm calling it bioinformed design,
انا اسميها التصاميم الحيوية،
and I think it's possible.
و اعتقد انه ممكن.
Thank you.
شكرًا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)